Vishvjitsinh (Vish) Ravalji

Web Developer

| Montreal QC, Canada | vishvajitravalji@gmail.com | +1-514-918-7149 |



in Linkedin



Portfolio



Github

SUMMARY

Web Developer with around 2 plus years of experience in the field of Software development. Experience in Design, Development, Testing and Deployment of responsive websites. Extensive knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Bootstrap. Good in OOPs concept and basic knowledge of Back-end, AWS and Bigdata technologies.

SKILLS

Experience with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, React, Bootstrap4, SCSS Knowledge of: REST, JSON, PHP, Java, Spring MVC, WordPress, SQL

UI/UX: jQuery, Tailwind CSS, Semantic-UI, Material-UI

Databases: MySQL, H2, Hive HUE, AWS Athena

Others: Postman, Git, GitHub, AWS

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer Intern

FANIQUE (Toronto, Canada)

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

Key Deliverables:

- FANIQUE is an innovative incubator for business in LIFESTYLE, TECH, and FASHION.
- Enhanced skill such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery.
- Worked on UI/UX and Mobile first applications.

Junior Web Developer

DIES Tech (Ahmedabad, India)

June 2018 - May 2019

Key Deliverables:

- Developed web-based applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap and CMS.
- Created and maintained mutual fund management platform that enabled our internal analytics team to increase reporting speed.
- Made changes to existing web pages according to the feedback received from the end users or clients.
- Managed database in MySQL and H2.

EDUCATION

Post Graduation in Big Data Science

Aug 2020 - July 2021 MCIT (Montreal, Canada)

Post Graduation in Full Stack JAVA Development

MCIT (Montreal, Canada) July 2019 – June 2020

Bachelors in Computer Science

GTU (Vadodara, India) Aug 2014 - July 2018

GPA: 3.7

CERTIFICATIONS

Udemy - React - The Complete Guide

Clever Programmer - Web Development Bootcamp 2021

Udemy - Building an E-Commerce Store Using Java Spring Framework

Udemy - The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp

PROJECTS (Portfolio)

Word Hunt (PWA) (

- Word Hunt React App is a PWA App to find meaning, synonyms and pronunciation of any word in 12 languages.
- Fetched open source Api from "https://api.dictionaryapi.dev/api/"
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, JS ES6, Material UI, React, Axios, API, ThemeMode, PWA

Food Order Cart (1)

- Its a react app to count order number and final amount.
- Implemented cart modal.
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, React, React Context, Ref, Modal

Movie API Table (1)

- Retrieved Movie data using React and JSON Server.
- API: https://skyit-coding-challenge.herokuapp.com/movies
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, React, JavaScript ES6, React-Bootstrap, Material-ui.

Contact Manager (1)

- Contact Manager is a web-app to call contact from JSON Server.
- transformed JSON data.
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, React, JavaScript ES6, Router, Json-Server, Axios, API, Material-ui

User and Age Manager (

- It has functionalities to handle data of User & Age.
- Execute error modules.
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, React, JavaScript ES6

Expense Tracker (7)

- Its a responsive web to keep tracking of daily expenses.
- You can find expenses of past months.
- Skill: HTML5, CSS3, React, JavaScript ES6, JSON

Job filter tool SaaS ()

- Its a tool which has search and filter functionality.
- Derived data from JSON file.
- Skill: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JSON

ETL pipeline of GBFS(BIXI) data (

- Implemented an automatic ETL pipeline for JSON data files of BIXI.
- Downloaded and transformed JSON files to CSV and write them on the HDFS.
- Used Hive JDBC to execute a cross join between your two external tables and load data into the final table
- Skill: Scala, Spark Streaming, Kafka, Zookeeper, SQL, Hive, HDFS, Hadoop, Parquet and Avro

Task Management System \bigoplus \bigcap

- Build a full-stack web app to allow users to do CRUD operations.
- It's managed by Leader, Member and Admin.
- Skill: Java, Spring, MVC, Maven, JSP, H2 DB

Automated Wheel-Chair

- Completed project on Automated wheel chair that allows handicapped person to operate from mobile device.
- Worked on microcontrollers such as Raspberry Pi and Arduino
- Skill: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS and IoT